Hiu Mei Fu

UX / UI + Graphic Designer

in linkedin.com/in/mei-fu/ https://meifuux.github.io/

Skills

UX Concepts UI Design

User Research Design Systems

User Flow Design Psychology

Brand Guidelines User Journey

Prototyping Responsive Design

Wireframing Communication

Tools

Adobe XD Figma Sketch InVision

Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffects, InDesign, XD)

HTML, CSS & JavaScript

Education

Bachelor of Science In Creative Media

Aug 2015 - Oct 2019 · 3.51 GPA · 1st Honor City University Of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Certifications

Google UX Design Professional Certificate

Coursera | Google

Credential ID: 9JDNBHW3KQ9P

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Google

Credential ID: 3EH DR6 67L

Languages

English, Mandarin, Cantonese

Awards

Hong Kong ICT Awards 2020

Certification of Merit, Student Innovation

Profile

I am an aspiring UI/UX & Graphic designer with 2+ years of strong experience in creating user-centered design solutions that solve complex problems. With strong sense of creativity, collaboration and empathy that drive business value and enhance user engagement.

Experience

UX/UI & Graphic Designer

Orange Data Limited • Dec 2022 - Present | Freelance Mar 2022 - Nov 2022 | On-Site | Hong Kong

- · Designed engaging B2C platforms, including website, mobile web, app, for World Entertainment's casino gaming, utilizing UX/UI design principles based on user
- · Increased user engagement by 25% and website traffic by 40% through website redesign and optimization efforts.
- · Created effective marketing and promotional materials to drive B2B & B2C customer interest and increase sales.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams using Figma and clear communication to ensure successful project delivery.

Junior Web Designer

Semeiotics Group (Asia) Limited • Mar 2021 - Nov 2021 | On-Site | Hong Kong

- · Revamped website content and design for major clients, including: Gold Peak Technology Group Limited and Genji Kyoto
- · Increased website traffic by 33% and maximized user engagement by implementing effective design strategies.
- · Utilizing UI design best practices and aligning with client business needs and value.
- · Implemented responsive and SEO-optimized websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript within CMS platforms such as WordPress and Squarespace. Streamlined website performance.
- · Managed multiple web projects, ensuring they met functional requirements, adhered to timelines, and underwent rigorous testing.

Technical Artist

SenMedia Limited • Nov 2020 - Mar 2021 | Freelance | Hong Kong

- · Led government website revamp, optimizing information architecture for enhanced user experience with UX/UI design principles.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including programmers, clients, project manager & the CEO, leveraging teamwork and communication skills for successful project delivery and customer satisfaction.
- · Employed user research and iterative design methods to create user-centered designs that met business goals and needs with data-driven design decisions.
- · Utilized Adobe XD and interactive prototype reviews for efficient design processes and client communication